Instructor…All right, let's start off
here. We were, I think, wrapping up kind
of our overview, and here's just a
little, simple map of where the
locations of some of the key Pauline
epistles to the churches are found. Of
course, Rome, Italy, Corinth in the
south of Greece, Thessalonica further to
the north in Greece, Philippi even
further – and further to the north in
Greece, Ephesus, which is on the Western
Turkish Coast, what is Western Turkey
today, Colossae a little further inland.
All Colossae is today is a hill – is a
mound, basically.
If you go to Colossae today, none of it
has really been dug up at all. It's one
of the few remaining untouched biblical
archaeological sites. My understanding
is, is that they're working, I think, to
get ready to do a dig there, but so far
that has been completely left alone. If
you go to Laodicea or Hierapolis, which
are cities that are in a triangle in
that region, those two cities are quite
developed in terms of archaeological
sites, with a lot of rich history,
particularly in the couple of
generations after the time of the New
Testament. But Colossae has yet to be
developed as an archaeological site.
And in Galatia, you'll see there's no
marking of a particular city there, and
that obscures two things. One is a
debate about – the major thing is the
debate about which – where we're talking
about in Galatia. Galatia is a region
more than a particular city. And so,
there are two theories: There's a
Northern Galatian Theory and a Southern
Galatian Theory.
I don't know how to make an analogy for
it other than to say it's the difference
between writing between – to Dallas/Fort
Worth versus writing to Houston, okay,
northern versus southern Texas. But
anyway, so some of the debate is related
to whether we're dealing with the north
or the south of Galatia. And there's no
city attached to it, as is obvious –
there's no dot there – because that not
only could depend on what theory you
develop, but then once you do that,
you're covering a region and not a
particular locale.
Most of these letters that Paul wrote to
these regional areas – this is an
important point – were not just directed
strictly to the community to which they
written, but became – that city became a
hub for the various communities that
were gathered around it. So, for
example, the letter to the Ephesians in
all likelihood circulated up and down
the western coast, so the letter that
got written to Ephesus would have
eventually circulated its way to
Colossae.
There's a letter to the Laodiceans that
we don't have. At least we think there
was a letter to the Laodiceans that we
don't have. That would have circulated
in a similar kind of manner. And so
these cities oftentimes operated as kind
of hubs or headquarters for the
communities in the area and created –
and there was kind of an
inner-communication network, if you want
to think of it that way, that existed
between these churches as they passed
materials backward and forwards, as
Pauline – more people who worked with
Paul – moved, in some cases, from site
to site and gave oversight to some of
what was going on. Yeah, Dan.
Student…Would it have been as efficient
as the lost letters, like, a couple of
days and it's there?
Instructor…It would have been – well, it
would have been as efficient as the
travel was to the time period, which is
basically that you would cover – if you
did it by foot, you might cover up to 20
miles a day. If you did it by horse, you
might cover double or triple that,
depending on hard you pushed.
Student…So it was widespread, right.
Instructor…Yeah, what?
Student…It was widespread. They did have
lots of people doing it.
Instructor…Well, they had a few people
doing it. I wouldn't say it would be
widespread. There were a few people
engaged in commerce who were going back
and forth. But most people did not
travel like we do today. They stayed
pretty much in one place and were used
to, very much, to one locale. Yes.
Student…I'm trying to think. Did you say
that, like, this was Paul's intentions
or is that kind of more [crosstalk] –
Instructor…Well, I think – I don't know
whether it was Paul's intention, per se,
or it's just the way things worked
between these communities. These
communities would have needed their
mutual support because by choosing to be
in the church, oftentimes, you're
choosing to isolate yourself socially.
And so, this would have been one of the
ways for mutual encouragement, would be
for these communities to stay in some
contact with one another.